BELAL MOHSEN

Montreal, QC \(\) (438) 630-3847 \(\square \) belal4mohsen@gmail.com \(\subseteq \) (inkedIn | GitHub | WebSite

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

A passionate and driven software developer with 4+ years of experience working on Al and software development projects. Well-versed in Java, Python, data science, deep learning, machine learning, natural language processing, edge and cloud computing, and big data. An excellent communicator with strong collaboration skills. Seeking opportunities as a software developer.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Languages: Java, Python, familiar with Golang and JavaScript

Web-Designing: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap and started learning React-Js

ML & DL Technologies: Tensorflow, Keras, LSTM, GRU, Pandas, Numpy, Matplotlib, Seaborn,

PyQt5, NLTK, BERT, Scipy, SciKit-Learn

Databases: PostgreSQL, MySQL, SQLite, familiar with MongoDB

Hardware Kits: Nvidia Jetson Boards, Arduino, Raspberry Pi, FPGA, PIC Micro-controller

Other: Docker, VM, Microsoft Azure, CI/CD Pipeline

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

FaimData Montreal, QC

Software Developer Intern

May 2022 - Aug 2022

- Troubleshot, debugged, and upgraded existing computer vision software.
- Refactored applications written in JavaScript and re-coded them in Golang.
- Deployed deep learning models on Nvidia Jetson boards using Docker containers.
- Coded, improved, and maintained distributed sensors' data collector software using Python and C.

Era Novum Assemblage

Montreal, OC

Furniture Assembler

Sep 2021 - Apr 2022

- Led a team of 5 responsible for assembling and repairing motorized reclining sofas.
- Ensured team worked collaboratively to complete work safely and on time.

Jordan University of Science & Technology

Ar Ramtha, Jordan

Al Developer & Research Assistant

Oct 2018 - Mar 2020

- Developed, built, and tested AI applications for the Computer Engineering and Software Engineering Departments.
- Collected structured and unstructured data using different sources and methods.
- Prepared collected data (usually large data sets) by cleaning and eliminating errors; converted unstructured data to structured and proper form based on the task.
- Used visualization tools like Matplotlib and Seaborn to present data.
- Built, trained, validated, and tested ML and DL models against the collected data to solve real-world problems.
- Deployed the training models; built and created GUI-based applications using PyQt5.

Yemeni University of Science & Technology Instructor & Graduate Projects Supervisor

Amman, Jordan

Jun 2016 - Dec 2019

 Helped students develop ideas and generate Al and ML applications to solve real-world problems.

- Supervised, mentored, and led students' groups during their work on graduation projects
- Taught IT and mathematics classes; reviewed and evaluated group projects.

EDUCATION

Vanier College, Montreal, Quebec	2024
ACS - Software Development Secure Desktop, Mobile and Web Applications	
 Current GPA: 99.4/100 	
Jordan University of Science & Technology, Ar Ramtha, Jordan	2018
M.Sc Computer Engineering	
Received mention of excellence for GPA of 3.99/4.00	
Aleppo University, Aleppo, Syria	2012
B.Sc Computer Engineering	

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

• **Volunteer** - Bienvenue à NDG, Montreal - 2021

CERTIFICATES & TRAINING

- English Courses HSM Adult Education Centre, Montreal 2022
- AZ-900 Microsoft Azure Fundamentals Udemy 2022
- Deep Learning Al TensorFlow Developer Professional Certificate Coursera 2021
- Machine Learning Engineering for Production Specialization Coursera 2021
- Francization Ministry of Immigration, Francization, and Integration 2021

LANGUAGES

- **English** (fluent)
- French (basic)
- Arabic (native)

SKILLS

Software development, Web applications, Front-end development, Data science, deep learning, machine learning, natural language processing, big data, edge and cloud computing